Andrew Cumming

Barrie, Ontario andrew.e.cumming@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://andrewec.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-cumming/
Stack Overflow Careers: https://careers.stackoverflow.com/AndrewC

GitHub: https://github.com/AndrewEC

Summary

I'm a professional software developer with over 6 years of experience primarily in the areas of developing Java and Node based microservices, system integration, continuous deployment, and production application support all within the context of an agile, often scrum like, way of working.

Skills

Languages: Java, Typescript, Python, C#

Frameworks: Spring Boot, WebFlux, Node.js, NestJS, FastAPI, Angular 2+

Cloud: OpenStack, PCF, Bluemix, Dynatrace, Splunk, UrbanCode Deploy, Jenkins

Databases: MariaDB, MySQL, MongoDB

Misc: MS Word, MS Excel, Outlook 365, Mac OS, Windows OS, Postman, SoapUI, Intellij, VS Code, Git,

Github

Professional Experience

Business Banking Portal Development (API Developer/RBC) (2019/Current)

- Developed multiple Java/Spring Boot/Maven stateless microservices using a scrum like methodology in 2 week sprint cycles
- Ensured product quality through the implementation of granular automated tests including unit tests, integration tests with WireMock, contract tests with PACT, and mutation tests using PIT, for execution on a mature CI/CD pipeline
- Ensured application resiliency and banking portal scalability by taking advantage of latest Spring conventions including reactive and asynchronous paradigmsdeveloping semi-

- transparent proxies for caching server-to-server communications, and creating optimized database ORM queries, relationships, and indexes
- Implemented integrations with external service provides like Verified.Me and SSO to other financial and accounting portals
- Applications built deployed via Jenkins and Urban Code Deploy through an automated continuous integration pipeline and hosted on the Pivotal Cloud Foundry platform
- Worked with QA and QE teams to design and setup test data for verifying complex flows and simulating complex companies setups and legal agreements
- Debugged production level defects and issues using standard application logs and Dynatrace tracking
- Designed and implemented structured database schemas using MariaDB for features like user preferences and approval workflows with the help of Liquibase and Spring JPA
- Expanded communication and presentation skills through dedicated Ezra coaching sessions

Online Banking Service Development (Developer/RBC) (2017-2019)

- Developed multiple backend services using Spring Boot and Spring MVC with Maven to support various online banking features like self-serve loan management, GIC purchase and renewal, and online foreign currency ordering
- Created multi-channel applications that support customer and employee assisted channels utilizing LDAP/SPNEGO for automatic employee authentication
- Developed upon, and maintained, legacy Websphere applications running on a remote Windows VM
- Worked with internal security teams to identify and resolve application security vulnerabilities through an internal pen-testing process
- Applications primarily built and deployed via Jenkins and Urban Code Deploy through an automated continuous integration pipeline and hosted on the Bluemix platform
- Developed, largely, in a Waterfall style methodology with dedicated quality assurance team members

Developer (Co-op/RBC) (2016)

- Analyzed existing Enterprise Java applications running on the Websphere server on remote Windows VMs
- Developed a prototype MEAN stack application to enable developers the ability to create mock cloud server endpoints capable of dynamic and meaningful responses through simple building blocks without the need for any complex coding
- Codebase managed and revisioned through SVN and Git
- Troubleshot remote Windows VM development environment issues
- Developed stories using the standard waterfall methodologies

Technical System Analyst (Co-op/RBC) (2015)

- Created a prototype Android Wearable based app for making ATM withdrawals in a more convenient and quick manner without the use of a typical debit card
- Created a prototype web application for polling, similar to Straw Poll, for gathering feedback and questions during live presentations using Angular 1 + MongoDB and hosted on a private Bluemix cloud instance
- Adapted feature base, and expanded existing features, based on internal client feedback and changing requirements
- Developed in an informal think-tank like structure

Employment History

Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, Ontario **Developer** (Spring Boot/Angular) – 2019 (Current)

Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, Ontario **Developer** (Spring MVC/Sprint Boot/J2EE) – 2017 – 2019

Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, Ontario **Developer** (Co-op) – 2016

Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, Ontario **Technical Systems Analyst** (Co-op) – 2015

Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, Ontario IT Accessibility (Co-op) – 2015

Ministry of Community and Social Services – Toronto, Ontario **Technology Accessibility Analyst** (Co-op) – 2014

Education

Centennial College – Toronto, Ontario Software Engineering Technology, 2012 to 2016 – Advanced Diploma